VARNA VINCENT

6692046244, varnamvmv@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A passionate developer with four years of experience, developing web and mobile applications in vacation rental and healthcare domains. Known for strong technical, analytical and organizational abilities. Excellent team player with strong work ethic and personal integrity. Strong technical expertise in the latest web and mobile technologies and comfortable following agile practices.

SKILLS

- **Strong:** Core Java, Javascript
- Intermediate: Git, VueJs, PHP, Laravel, HTML5, Ionic framework, Apache Camel, REST, SOAP Webservices, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, AngularJS, XML, XSLT, AJAX
- Familiar: Spring, Oracle, Maven

SIDE PROJECTS

 <u>Number Sense Game</u> - An interactive game to help you visualize numbers and develop your number sense.

EXPERIENCE

Nibodha Technologies, Infopark, Kakkanad (2015 - 2016)

Senior Software Developer

Care Services [May 2016 – July 2016]

- Developed a mobile app that helps the general practitioner to find nearby community services for patients
- Tools used: AngularJs 1, Ionic Framework, Firebase, Git

Always On Vacation [January 2016 – May 2016]

- Contributed to development of a bulk data processing framework Databridge
- Developed APIs and integrated data modules for vacation rental property suppliers
- Tools used: Core Java, Maven, Apache Camel, Spring, MongoDB, MySql, Oracle, Git

Mobile Insight [October 2015 – December 2015]

- Developed a highly scalable messaging module for communicating store visit updates
- Tools used: Core Java, Maven, Git, Spring

Sos [March 2015 – September 2015]

- Developed a responsive admin website, tablet app and a cross-platform mobile app for the SWAT team and employees in an organization to be used in the event of a catastrophe.
- Tools used: Angularjs, javascript, Parse db, Ionic framework, Bootstrap, Grunt, Yeoman

Zerone Consulting Pvt. Ltd., Infopark, Kakkanad (2012 - 2015)

Software Engineer – Level 3

Acer Web Development [November 2013 – March 2015]

- Led a team of 3 engineers to enhance ACER's Australian website for their distributors and retailers.
- Developed additional modules for budget forecasting and special pricing for bulk demands.
- Enhanced existing modules to facilitate the claim process between Acer's customers and the various business units within Acer.
- Tools used: Java, Servlets, Spring 2.0, XML, XSLT, Oracle db, Maven, JBOSS server, HTML, Javascript, ¡Query, AJAX

HealthFabric [January 2013 – October 2013]

- Contributed to the development of HealthFabric, a tablet based solution, allowing patients to record their health and social care information.
- Contributed to the development of a switchyard application for routing web services between HealthFabric and SugarCRM
- Tools Used: Phonegap, jQuery, Ajax, SQLite DB, Switchyard, JBOSS, REST, SOAP web services, Core Java, Maven

Data Scrapper [August 2012 – December 2012]

- Involved in a team of five, in extracting data from various healthcare congress meeting abstracts.
- Tools used: Microsoft Excel 2013, VBA, Macro

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

• Currently developing a website for a non profit organization in Arizona, <u>Collaborating for a Cause</u> using PHP, Laravel, PostgreSQL.

EDUCATION

Prospective graduate student in Software Engineering, 2017-2019

Santa Clara University, CA

Bachelors in Computer Science and Engineering, 2008-2012

TocH Institute of Science and Technology, Arakkunnam

EXTRA CURRICULAR

- Master of ceremony at technical conferences hosted by <u>MobConf</u>.
- Active member of MobConf Technical Community.
- Event coordinator at Nibodha Technologies and Zerone Consulting.
- Member of Entertainment Committee at Zerone Consulting.